that that resulted in a single token. So
solid gold Magikarp is one token. And in
GPT2, if you ever mentioned solid gold
Magikarp, it thought you were saying
like, "F you" or something. You got to
look this up. There's like a YouTube
video about it. Anytime you said that,
it would respond. It would like curse at
you. It was really funny.
Best part of when you can just, you
know, critical think, right?
Yeah, dude.
[Music]
All righty. Sup, y'all. We've got the
This Week in Bug Bounty segment. Uh for
this week, we've got this week's This
Week in Bug Bounty segment. Um and what
we've got on the docket this time is a
couple updates. Um, yes, we hack uh has
a new article that came out not too long
ago uh recon series 6 and this is
entitled uh excavating hidden artifacts
with wayback machine and other web
archive tools which I thought was
particularly timely today because I am
taking a break from hacking something
during which I just had a breakthrough
using these tools um to come and tell
you about these tools. So, if you're not
familiar with how to use Way More or if
you're still using Gal like Yavoy was,
uh, then you should definitely read
through this article and kind of get up
to date on using Way More to do a little
bit more thorough investigation of the
archive, uh, Wayback Archive. Um,
definitely a pivotal piece of technology
for hackers. Also, I know that they're
always raising funds, like they're
always like, "Please give us money so
that we can continue running this
nonprofit." Uh, we need to keep this
thing alive, guys, because countless
crits have been popped because of the
wayback machine. Um, and this article is
a really great way to sort of get up to
date on it. Um, using way more, uh,
Linkfinder, GA, um, all sorts of stuff.
So, definitely check it out. Uh, all
right. Second update is from a Hacker 1
disclosed report. Um, this one was
report 2817648.
And check this out, guys. This is a uh
C++ uh related error where uh sign bits
der sign traits derive bits which is a
C++ function in the Node.js core um
source code may incorrectly call throw
exception on user supplied input in the
background process crashing all of
Node.js. So um the the reason this was
relevant is because it actually uh you
know you can affect availability
completely and you know things getting
passed into these cryptographic
functions are often uh untrusted user
input. Um so this is definitely
something you want to keep an eye out
for. I kind of went and checked at the
um at the patch for this and essentially
the patch was just checking whether it
should be able to throw or not. Um and
so I think that there's a couple ways
this could be exploited. Obviously, we
don't want to affect availability too
much, but if you have some way to
fingerprint, it's running on an older
version of Node.js, then uh that could
be this could be a really cool attack.
And while I was researching it, I
actually came across this uh other
exploit that was released in that same
uh May 2025 update, which is a uh
improper header block termination in
LHDP, which is a piece of um uh Node.js.
And this was actually found by Ken
Ballas, who uh is the guy from HTB
Garden, who we've talked about a couple
times. And essentially, it allows for
improper termination of HTP1 headers uh
using SLRN RX rather than the required
SLR rn.
Um so very very interesting piece. If
you're interested in uh request
smuggling, this could be something that
you could use to potentially uh trigger
some really impactful request smuggling
vulnerabilities. it only got a medium
and didn't get a ton of attention
somehow. Um, but I know that a lot of
you guys have really intense HTTP um,
request smuggling automation out there,
so this would be a good one to toss on
in. Um, all right. That's all for the
this weekend bug bounty segment. Let's
go back to the show.
All right. Listen, dude. I've got I've
got a little bit of a bone to pick with
you. Okay. Um, this blog post, this is
how they tell me Bug Bounty ends.
Is this is this FUD, dude? Is this FUD
or is this not FUD? Because I read it
and I was like a little bit moved, but
also I'm like I don't know. I've been in
some meetings with you where you felt
pretty moved. Yeah, I I I am I am moved.
I am moved. And and and I'll I'll be
transparent about it. I mean it
definitely this blog post made me
realize that if I want to be on
the if I really really do want to stay
ahead of the curve right by a lot then I
need to start doing you know AI
agent-based hacking now you need to be
more enhanced by AI yeah yeah and if I
want to perform at at the highest level
y right I mean I think I think that the
reason why I tweeted it in such a way
where it's like you might love this or
you I hate this. And the reason why the
blog post even reads in like an
ambiguous like just slightly ambiguous
way is because I I feel the same way,
right? I'm I'm just I'm in the same boat
as you. Like it's hard for me to even
tell if it is FUD, but it's just my
honest opinion. And you know, maybe
maybe you'll tease out that haven't read
the blog post. Give us like the TLDDR of
it. Uh I think the major points I wanted
to make was people who are putting their
head head in the sand and they think
that AI is not going to be able to do
what human hackers can do, they're
wrong. They're crazy. I think that like,
you know, I've met with a lot of hackbot
founders. I'm an adviser for Ethiak. Um,
and so I think that these models can
definitely hack and I think that the
people on the other end of the spectrum
are wrong, too. Like people who think
that, you know, all the bug bounty
hunters are going to be out of their job
in six months or a year are also wrong.
And so the the attack that I, you know,
this blog post is basically me laying
out what I think is going to happen. I
guess I can give you like a two-se
summary of that. I basically think that
the first step in the transition is
going to be called like hacker in the
loop or you know basically human in the
loop but you're gonna have like top
hackers like you or like you know other
top hackers using AI to hack faster,
better, smarter and also to like the the
AI actually needs us to vet a lot of the
what what it thinks is true positive
because it just takes a lot of context
and a lot of skill to know really when
something is a true positive. Are we
going to have that context though if
we're not in the weeds? Like that is one
of the things that's really interesting
to me. Like sure, I can be like, "Hey,
look, here's the single point of failure
in the system, right? If you can fuzz
this and get it to return a domain that
is not, you know, in this specific allow
list or whatever, then we've got an SSRF
or whatever, right? And then hand it to
the AI and let it do all of the
intelligent fuzzing, you know, and in
context aware stuff." Uh, but that's me,
you know, using the AI sort of as a tool
and my context is greater than the AI's
context. And I'm wondering if it's ever
going to get to the point where my
context is lower and the AI's context is
greater and that is how we hack. Yeah.
So, let's just for the topic of this
conversation, it might not be called
this, but for this conversation, let's
call that a blackbot hacking like
hackbot, right? So, so for blackbox
hackbots that basically are just like
set to go hack on a domain and then it
comes back. like less of a tool and more
of like a fully embodied agent, right?
And then it comes back to you and it's
like, hey, these are the leads. I think
for a lot of those, you will be able to
very quickly like let's say it came back
to you as a front-end guy and it's like,
hey, I think there's a client side patch
reversal here and here's my request
that's a PC and here's the response from
the here's the response that appears and
here's the screenshot from the headless
browser. You know, is this true? You
know, you don't think you'd be able to
vet it without having to like dig up
some context? Absolutely. You could.
Yeah. Yeah. And so I think that that's
the case. There will be some that are
really complex. It's like I don't know
if this is working or not, you know, but
I think that in general those are going
to be the ones that are the last to be
found. I think that like you know the AI
the AI says I think XSS is popping here
because here's the input, here's the
response from the server and here's the
screenshot of the alert box and you're
like well that's a pretty closed shut
case, right? Yeah. Exactly. And so uh
yeah, so I think that it's it just
really varies vulnerability to
vulnerability. And maybe that's why it
gets so complex to like talk about is
because there are some bugs that AI will
like not be able to find for 10 years
maybe or 30 years, right? Like but there
are a lot of other vulnerabilities that
I think AI will be able to find. And as
soon as the price point is low enough
where they can spin up well I always
call this the hackbot singularity. But
if there's a point at which you can spin
up a hackbot and it costs $10 to run but
it makes you $20 in bounties any person
any sane person is just going to spin up
as many as they can until it becomes
nonprofitable. Right. Right. Yeah. And
and I mean that's the same sort of thing
you see with applying those same
principles from business with
advertising and stuff like that, right?
Like if you have an advertising model
that is generating you $10 and cost $5,
then you're just going to keep pressing
that button as fast as you possibly can.
Yeah. Yeah. And and um I can definitely
see that happening. Uh, I definitely
agree with you that it is more I I think
I think there will be a lot of value to
these um agents that are, you know,
black body agents, but I I I think that
the the main thing that I'm convinced on
right now after our our talks and and
after just a couple timely interactions
plus your blog post, right? Like I I I
fed something that I was working on to
uh Gemini the other day and Gemini like
took it and like ran some tools to parse
it and like and and really did some and
it was actually it's interesting that we
were talking about this off air about
how you know it's a little bit less good
with binary based stuff. Um this was one
of those cases where it was like B 64
encoded binary protocol and it like
dealt it and I was like oh my gosh this
is crazy. Yeah, that's a little pro tip.
Anytime you're dealing with something
that requires like tough accuracy, I was
dealing with like a neat like AI related
kind of bypass I was working on where I
needed to convert the data I was trying
to leak into binary, but where the zero
was a new line and the one was a uh
space. And so like uh I wanted the model
to basically write me a payload or like
write a little server that would like
handle that well and stuff. And because
it was like weird syntax like you know
the AI's never been trained on binary
that's spaces and new lines probably. I
I it kept messing up the format and I
was like just use your code interpreter
tool to convert it. So then it like
wrote it in binary then converted it for
me in like its little code interpreter
and that's like a really good pro tip
like when you're dealing with stuff like
you're talking about like just tell it
to say like hey you keep being
inaccurate use your code interpreter
tool here. Yeah that's that's that's a
great call. Yeah the code interpreter
the in that specific environment did
phenomenally well and I was really uh I
was kind of like jaw-dro moment on that.
I was like, I got to start integrating
this a little bit more. And then your
blog post came out like the same day and
I'm like, [__] [__] [__] [__] [__]
It does, it does take a lot of time to
write a good prompt sometimes for these
like really complex vulnerabilities that
we're often chasing down as hackers. But
I think that if you take the time to do
it and give it to smart models like the
latest Gemini 25 Pro or, you know, even
03 Pro, which just dropped, I think that
they'll often surprise you. Like I think
that a lot of hackers would be surprised
by how much um how much it would speed
them up or by how many just good ideas
it's going to have. Yeah. And just sort
of tangentally related to this and and
as a counterpoint to the whole agent
thing. Um I've been following a little
bit the Hackron AI folks. Y and u and
yeah and I think one of the founders I
forget who it was I can't find the tree
right now tweeted something out like
this is the future of hacking. I said
hackron AI to work on this and I went
and grabbed a coffee and then I came
back and I had four leads to follow,
right? And and then, you know, I went
and followed those and maybe popped one
of them or whatever, right? Yeah. And
and I think that is an interesting I
think that's an interesting take because
it's not necessarily saying that this
Hackron AI is going to just you know
you're going to go grab coffee and come
back Hackron like here's your report,
you know, but it it maybe it can
identify things that are higher signal
sketchy than normal programmatic tools
can. Yeah. Right. Uh or nonAI using
tools can and then you feed those leads
to, you know, a closer, right? We've
talked about this a little bit on the
pod before how you've got various people
in the with various skill sets in bug
bounty. A lot of some people are like
really good lead generators. Some of uh
you know as far as like finding sketchy
stuff, some people are really good
exploitationists, right? Or exploits,
right? And and they can close close the
uh you know the vone. Um and I I think
maybe another interesting position for
AI could be that it will produce really
good leads and hand it to a talented
exploitist to to close the loop on.
Yeah. So I this is something I've talked
about not only do I am an adviser for
one hackbot company but for the other
ones when I when I do like a call with
these founders as like kind of like a VC
scouting thing I will often give them
like really great advice just because I
love adding value to the world and I
want to see everything improve. Um, but
I I genuinely think that how these
hackbot companies handle leads is going
to be huge and and I think it's because
exactly what you're talking about,
right? Every lead is a potential vom.
And I think that some of the companies
are overindexing on fully blackbox when
the reason why I mentioned in my in my
blog post like the human in the loop
hackbot singularity as like a midterm
spot is because of exactly what you're
talking about. And here here's here's my
exact quote on what you were talking
about. I said, "One good hacker and a
hackbot system working together will be
able to out hack almost everyone from a
volume perspective." And that's what I
believe. I mean, if I could feed you a
list, Justin, of like, I don't know, 10
potential XSS and 10 potential CSPT and
10 potential RC via command injection,
and you're literally just like betting
them like, "Oh, yeah, that one is a bug.
Nope, that one's not. Yeah, that one
is." if they're actually a decently high
signal, even if it's only like 30%
accurate, like you would be able to make
a lot of money from just like reviewing
bugs. And it's almost like what we see
with the um critical thinkers
hackalongs, right? Is like um you know,
with the hackalongs, obviously we have a
ton of super talented hackers, you know,
participating in the hackalongs and and
in the critical thinking discord, but
I've been surprised by a couple people
that that, you know, I would I would
consider as like solid m like
intermediate hackers, right? you know,
that really are getting really good at
some stuff but are definitely fresher on
the scene, right? Um, and you know, when
we're hacking together, I'm going down
one route and then almost every single
time somebody will drop in the chat and
be like, "Hey, look at this sketchy
thing that I just found." Y, right? So,
I if if and I just love that, right?
Because it's like, okay, and then, you
know, I'll take that and close the loop
on it and exploit it or something like
that or maybe somebody else who's better
than me in the chat will do it, you
know, and it happens almost every time
we do a hackon, right? And and I think
that if if just applying this to AI, if
you can get the AI to be at at a level
of like a a intermediate hacker as far
as like um intuition of whether a
functionality is sketchy or not, then
essentially hacking becomes here's a
bunch of leads from an intermediate
hacker, skilled hacker. Now your job is
to be the closer. Yeah. I think it's
much more likely that it's able to find
the sketchy leads than it is to be able
to be a closer. Like I I think I think
that the closer is going to come later.
I I I do think that it's um big upside
the big advantage it has to closing is
infinite time like near infinite time
and infinite attempts, right? So if it's
trying to find a very specific payload
that will bypass a specific filter, it
can try infinitely, right? Assuming that
the the the financial incentives align,
it can literally try as many times as it
wants. And it has and it's infinitely
patient, right? And so I I think that
really that's the advantage on it being
a closer is that it can just try so many
things in such a short amount of time
and you can scale it up so well. But I
think in general it's going to be much
better at finding the weird things.
those people that have taken notes
really have a massive advantage now with
AI as well is like you know I have been
a largely intuition based and just reps
based hacker to this point and like you
know I don't have like a massive notion
or whatever filled with how I approach
every single target and every code from
every live hacking event and I'm really
wishing I did now because um there are
this is a massive opportunity for us to
take say hey you know sometimes if you
change the host post header, you know,
on a password reset, you know, then it's
going to trigger this thing and just
give them all of the weird [__] you've
seen, every single weird [__] you've
seen, right? And then and then hope that
it has the ability to properly implement
that and alert you if something looks
even remotely sketchy, you know, and and
draw those techniques back to your mind
because we've we've talked about this
time and time again, how, you know, some
bones are popular for a period and then
you stop testing those and you're like,
for whatever reason, you maybe got shiny
object syndrome and now you're looking
at for this new Well, I mean, none of us
are as disciplined as Space Raccoon to
go through like a spreadsheet of like
all the vans that I want to check across
every AI API endpoint, right? Yeah,
exactly. Yeah, it's it's it's a lot,
man. It's a lot. And and I think AI can
really help with that. So, yeah, man.
For those of you that have really good
detailed notes on your methodology, this
is like a big dub for you. Yeah, I think
so. Um, you know, me. I know he's I was
about to say that exact thing. I was
like, I know the guy who does that. Um,
yeah. So, I I don't know that I said all
of my other like major points that I
wanted to make with this. The the other
thing that I wanted to make a point of
is I just think like as kind of like
proof to like call my shot here is that
I think we'll hit that human in the loop
hackbot singularity by the end of the
year and there will be a company that
farms, you know, 500 to a,000
vulnerabilities by the end of the year.
And I think that that's going to be very
impressive. I mean, Expo is already like
the quote unquote top hacker in the US.
Um,
and I think that it's exactly what we're
talking about, right? I'm sure that it's
Dorado and Epotarmia or whatever. And
you know, honestly, the bug money
platforms need to decide how they're
going to handle that because it's kind
of a shared account. Yeah. Yeah. That's
interesting. But it is something that we
need to think about. Well, they hacker
one released something on that, right?
Like hacker one, hackbot. Yeah. and and
we like super um we super lightly
covered it on the pod, but uh there was
a a write up from um the one of the
co-founders uh Muel on welcome hackbots,
how AI is shaping the future of
vulnerability discovery. We'll link it
link it again. But yeah, I mean I I
think that they don't really have any
choice but to allow hackbots to Yeah,
they need to handle it compete. But
maybe there's a separate leaderboard for
or maybe you can flag a specific account
as like a hackbot account or something
like that. I don't know. Yeah. One. So,
so another thing that I want to get
across with it was just positivity
amidst job loss. Like I think that there
will be impact to hackers for sure in
the long term, but I think in the medium
term, people can be really encouraged
because one, we will need human in the
loop. So, I do think the hackers should
maybe think about what they want that to
look like and maybe either make it known
on social media or reach out to these
hack companies and be like, I would I
think that the best model for this is
like contract based work rather than
like hiring these buck hunters. Like bug
hunters love being fulltime. do and so
like I would love if the model is such
that I'm kind of like sponsored by
Ethiak or whatever and then I use that
in my daily driver to both improve their
product and splitting the bounties with
them and you know we kind of both get
the um exposure the exposure for it I
think that'd be a lot better but I mean
honestly even if you're if you're a bug
bing hunter and you are kind of worried
about this maybe looking to apply to
hack companies is a smart decision I do
think there will be a lot of money
wrapped up in this for multiple reasons.
One is it's just huge for humanity to
like be able to secure everything in an
automated fashion. Two, it's like a very
strong nation state related superpower.
Like I am a believer that AI alignment
is like a really big deal and the issues
that could arise from a you know
somewhat um unsafeely wielded AI like if
there's a you know a nation state that
we don't trust down the line and they're
using AI to do nefarious things they're
going to need to they're going to want
to use it for bio warfare and they're
going to want to use it for hacking. And
so like by
I don't know by contributing to this um
effort I think that you're kind of
helping humanity in in like a really
powerful way too. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So
anyway, my I mean just take my take away
from your blog and and just my
experiences at that point was really I
need to begin the process of taking my
methodology and what I'm doing and
getting it into prompts and getting it
into, you know, something that's ragable
or or something, you know, um so that
the AI can eventually use it once we
have uh particularly these more human in
the loop microbots sort of thing going
on. Um, so I don't know. It's a little
bit of a hard thing for me because I'm
like h I don't really feel like taking a
break from the hacking, you know, to
really dev on this a lot and try to get
it to a point where I can do this, but
I'm kind of at the point where I'm like,
I kind of need to do that. So yeah, two
thing two things and we're we're prone
to it on rabbit hole. So I'm just
telling you these so we don't forget to
touch them. One is what you're talking
about right now. I think that I want to
talk about the hacker kind of thought um
thought process as they exploit bugs.
But the second thing I want to talk
about with you is tokenization. I know
we talked about that off air and I want
to circle back to that. Yeah. And also I
want to Yeah. And what we need to do is
just go in the doc. Go over to the doc
right now. Um and write some of those
down. So token tokenization. Yeah. Um
and what was the other one you said? Uh
basically hacker's chain of thought.
Really? Hacker chain of thought. Yeah.
Yeah. And what is what was yours?
What mine was was this other other note
as well which is the reason that I got
out of the automation game um you know
back in like 2022 is that I don't like
coding as much as I like hacking. Yeah.
Right. And I found that I was spending a
lot of my time coding instead of
hacking. Y and that is that changed a
lot recently you know like with the
onset of of AI assisted coding. So, one
of the things I've considered is I I've
always that passive income piece or of
passively finding bugs is has been
really attractive. Um, but it was offset
by the the thing I didn't like which is
that I had to code all the time and that
that offset has been erased by AI a
little bit or at least lessened. So, I
am definitely putting more thought and
consideration into going back into the
automation game whether it be hard
automation or AI based automation um
with supplementation from from code
assisting AI.
Cool. Yeah. Yeah. So, the two things I
want to mention. One was the chain of
thought from hackers. This is just um
kind of a pro tip for one when you take
down your notes, but two I think for
these hackbot companies and three just
for other hackers. The ideal context for
an AI model when it's trying to exploit
a CSP is your thoughts. And I mean
literally Justin Gardner's thoughts
because I think you're probably one of
the foremost CSPT people, right? and you
have extremely good chain of thought in
your brain like basically your notes
like like you're what what why do you
think CSP exists here? Okay, write that
down. Okay, what is the first thing
you're going to attempt to check whether
it exists there? Okay, write that down.
Okay, it failed because of this. So your
next payload is going to be what and why
and okay that failed. Okay, your next
payload is going to be what and why? Oh,
it worked. Okay, cool. So you found it.
Okay, now how do we leverage this into a
vulnerability? Okay, what do you look
for next in the application? Okay, write
that down. Right? It's like basically
every thought you're having as you're
exploiting something is the ideal
context for an AI language model when
it's trying to exploit the exact same
thing. And so I've always wanted to have
like Sam Curry's internal I've called it
internal monologue. And I even made a
little app called like internal
monologue capture. Um I think that like
internal monologue capture is actually a
space for a product here. if there was
some if there was some way where it
would like continually ask you questions
or ask you to talk out loud and then it
would capture that for you. Um anyways,
I think expert expert internal monologue
capture is something me and Daniel
Nesler talked about over a year ago when
I was hanging out at his house at at um
RSA and I still key to today. So, dude,
absolut freaking lutely. And and I think
that is so hard to do. Like I and I have
a lot of experience with that because of
the the um menteeing, you know, mentor
mentee relationship where a lot of times
what I'll do sometimes with these with
these mentees is I'll hack on something.
I'll just narrate what I'm saying. Yes.
And it and my mentees are probably going
to be like, "Shut the [__] up, Justin."
Because what it actually sounds like is,
"Oh, guys, check this." Uh oh. And and
then I just like stop talking and
they're like, "What do you what do you
mean?" Um and I've been trying to get
better at it. Uh and and anybody who
listens to the um hackalongs also know
that I I am am very um prone to start
start narrating something and then get
hijacked by like, oh, I need to allocate
all of my mental resources to this one
thing really quickly and then and then
not finish my thought. But I I think as
you get more reps with that, that is a
very like is going to be a very valuable
skill. Uh, and especially if there's
some product like you're saying that
will essentially just be listening to me
talk because I feel like that is the
most natural way of conveying your
thoughts without friction to yourself
and then convert that into a chain of
reasoning that the AI can consume to
mimic your skill set in a specific area,
right? It becomes basically the perfect
system problem for a sub agent that
wants to exploit that same
vulnerability. Um, all right.
Tokenization. So, I found that quote
from Kaparthi. Yeah. So, if anyone's
listening and you don't know what
tokenization is, you need to go look it
up, but I'll summarize it in like two
sentences here. Tokenization is the way
that AI models view the world because
they've been trained on what are called
tokens. Tokens are just strings that are
associated to numbers. And those
floating port numbers are like what
technically the model outputs whenever
it, you know, answers your question or
whatever. It just gets converted back to
the token, which is back to the string,
which is sometimes a full word,
sometimes it's only a character. You can
look up tokenizers to see how it works.
But the whole point is tokeniz are the
root of all problems. So anyway, I
really love this. So this is this is
from Andre Kaparthy, the father of
modern LLMs and AI. He's like very
wellknown, well regarded. Why can't LLM
spell words? Tokenization. Why can't LLM
do super simple string processing tasks
like reversing a string? Tokenization.
Why is why are LLM's worst at non-ang
English languages like Japanese?
Tokenization. Why is LM bad at simple
simple math? Tokenization. Why did GPD2
have more than necessary trouble coding
in Python? Tokenization. Why did my lm
abrupt abruptly halt when I sent it the
string open bracket uh pipe end of text
pipe close bracket tokenization like why
does it break whenever I ask about solid
gold magikarp which you don't know about
you should go watch that YouTube video
it's called um solid gold magikarp what
the [__] you don't know about this
there's a thing called glitch tokens in
um so glitch tokens don't really exist
anymore but basically when they were
scraping the data for training data from
Reddit there was a few tokens like solid
gold Magikarp um camelc case but all
with with no spaces that that resulted
in a single token. So solid gold
Magikarp is one token and in GPT2 if you
ever mention solid gold Magikarp it
thought you were saying like f you or
something. You got to look this up.
There's like a YouTube video about it.
Anytime you said that it would respond.
It would like curse at you. It was
really funny. So you got to go look this
up. It's called glitch tokens and it's
by computer file on YouTube. I we'll put
it in the show notes. Anyways, so the
whole point is the our brains see the
world in like we're we're somehow able
to like switch between tokens. So we can
see the world as words like when we read
a book, but we can also see the world as
characters when we need to, right? Like
special characters. Um and so we have
like this kind of superpower that AI
doesn't have. And so I was bringing this
up to Justin before we started the the
the episode, but I wanted to mention it
because like AI doing things like HTTP
desync attacks or request smuggling,
it's basically impossible due to
tokenization because it can't count. It
doesn't really understand how to count
the number of spaces it's using. And
that's more of like an um arithmetic
thing, right? And so maybe it'll be able
to figure it out if it like writes two
parts of a of a smuggled request and
then it sends both of them into Python
code to count the number of characters
to then set the context link. But it's
going to be super hard. And that's an
example of a vulnerability that like I
don't know if AI will solve even 10
years down the road. Like it's going to
be a vulnerability that it's going to
take a very long time. Like where maybe
we don't even use tokenizers because
there's been some like theories that
eventually we can just make each
character a token and train a model
that's eventually good like that. And if
it viewed the world in characters, I
think it could potentially pull it off.
But anyways, um tokenization is really
fascinating and interesting and I think
that it does impact the amount of
vulnerabilities that can and cannot get
automated at the moment. I I definitely
didn't think about the fact that before
you mentioned it right right before this
episode that these LLMs are, you know,
thinking and living in in the token
world. Yes. From an output perspective
as well as an input. Like I knew that
from an input perspective, but they're
also outputting tokens. And if they
don't have access to, you know, a
specific set of tokens, then they can
know they're not going to output or or
maybe if the waiter weights are off, you
know, they're not going to output the
token that you need. even though like
that was very clearly iterated as the
the purpose or whatever. Yeah. And
that's where I think the difference
comes between like actual artificial
intelligence and you know fabricated
artificial intelligence here. Um and and
that is something that I I really hadn't
hadn't thought about because I will I
will challenge I will challenge your
last assumption there. We also
hallucinate. Sometimes we can't think of
the word. Sometimes it pops up in a
different way. Like just because the the
method of thinking I mean I don't think
that they're conscious. I don't think
that they have us all and we don't have
to get in all that. But I do think that
like just because the way in which these
top models think doesn't mirror exactly
how we think, I don't think that means
they're not necessarily reasoning.
There's some really interesting research
from anthropic that shows that even
before a model outputs a token, it
passes through different circuits in its
internal next token prediction that that
mimics very similar thinking. like it's
it's bouncing around on different topics
that are all related to the answer even
before it emits a single token. It's
very very fascinating stuff. Yeah, that
is that is very interesting. Definitely
not smart enough to to make an you know
qualified assertion about that. That's
fine. But but you're what you're talking
about there about like the words is like
very fascinating. There are some weird
token um I've been using cursor or sorry
wow chorus. Chorus is like a really cool
thing. I used to use misti.app now I use
chorus to like ask one question to
multiple models at the same time. If you
haven't used it, it's great. But I saw
someone talking about it on X and they
were like, you know, Gemini 25 Pro
putting in the cheeky Russian there.
They asked the English question and it
responded in all the models that it was
answering in parallel responded in
English, but Gemini 25 Pro threw in a
random Russian word and it meant the
exact same. Like you could understand it
if you read it in English because it was
it was like um according to it was some
word that you could easily tell what it
should have been in English. Um, but it
clearly just lived in the latent space
of the weight at the exact same spot.
And so it just picked the wrong token,
you know, as it was passing through. And
so anyway, stuff like that's really
interesting and I'm surprised we don't
see more of it. But yeah, definitely
definitely interesting. And and I think
going back to the human, you know,
thinking versus AI thinking, I
definitely don't know enough about that
to make a conjecture, but I do think
that, like you said, it affects the
granularity of what the AIS can output.
And I think that perhaps I'm I'm
misconstruing how human neural networks
work, but I think that a deeper
understanding like conceptual
understanding of what a character is and
what you know a character string looks
like um is something that differentiates
and and and as I'm saying that I'm also
realizing though that as as a beginner,
you think about an XSS payload as an XSS
payload, not as an image tag. and a
source attribute and you know an invalid
source attribute and an on- error
attribute and you know like so you know
that's what exactly what uh you know
beginner hackers are doing when they're
copy and pasting these excess payloads
is like they consider that one token
rather than you know a deeper concept or
different understanding of that specific
payload. Um I know you've only got one
minute but I had that exact same
thought. I thought about how you could
plug the hole of tokenization character
by character would be basically to
imagine getting a whole bunch of um
conversations like simulated
conversation. You know how they like do
um training on like back and forth
conversations. Imagine if there was a
bunch of conversations like fake
conversations between like me and an AI
or you and an AI or whatever where it
was basically like quizzing it on
characters. So like basically what I'm
trying to say is like I wonder if we
gave these top AI models a whole bunch
of content about like what a character
is and how it's different than like the
word like though like for example what
are the tokens in the word strawberry
and it was expected to respond s t r a w
b e if like if we gave it like a
trillion examples of those and threw
that into the training set if it would
develop its own sense of what a
character is in such a way that would
improve the output. I actually genuinely
think that could work. Um but anyways,
it was just a thought I had. Well, very
interesting, dude. Okay. I like you
said, I do have a hard stop, but um and
I might throw you to the wolves here a
little bit, Joseph. But um I think the
conversation that or the concept you
gave me about um context engineering is
really interesting. So, I don't know if
you want to talk about that. You could
bleep it. Richard could bleep it if you
don't want to. Uh but if you felt like
it, you could spend a couple minutes
just sort of explaining how difficult
that problem is and how relevant it is
to hackers. or we can cover at a
different time. Either way. Cool. Do you
have time to say for or you gonna drop
it? No, I'm I got to bounce. Okay, cool.
I'll stay describe it. You got it, man.
All right. Peace. Peace. Yeah. So, me
and Justin, before we hopped on the air,
we're talking about what I'm calling
context engineering. It came out of a
blog post from Horishi, but also the
founder of Lang Chain, his name is
Harrison Chase, was talking about um
context engineering and how it's going
to be really important. I think it's
like basically if you imagine AI as like
this bleeding technology and then you
imagine that um the way in which you
like develop and make uh what are they
called agents like this is kind of like
the year of agents is then kind of
breaking technology on top of AI so like
we have like agentic behavior and then
on top of that there's like sub agents
and how do you hand over context from
some agents to other agents um is what
Horishi in this blog post he posted
about um basically we may talk about
this in a future episode but Karishi
Olle is um the best wielder of AI in my
opinion and he wrote a blog post all
about how he was reversing the minifi JS
of claude code from anthropic it's like
oh hackers want to do that all the time
so I think that'd be really interesting
and so I shared it in the critical
thinkers chat multiple times but um in
there he he he calls these intermediates
but it's basically like the information
that he has that you have to hand off to
get a task done. And so his his kind of
three examples are you have to sometimes
hand off information to yourself when
you go to work on the same project on
the next day, right? But then that
that's like the easiest form of handoff.
Then the next step up is like you're
handing it off to someone who also knows
the project and the company really well.
And then the next step up is like
handing it to someone who doesn't know
it well or to an AI system that doesn't
have all the context of like your
company or your life or all the things
that are going on. And so I think that's
like pretty interesting. And um it's
basically how do you manage context
between agents? And I think that's going
to be really really key from a hackbot
perspective as well, right? Because you
may have like a core hackbot that hands
off something to an agent and it doesn't
pass back enough context for the core
agent to really make a true distinguish
like a true validation of whether or not
what the sub agent found is like a true
positive or a false positive. And so
anyways, that's just a cool hard problem
to solve and um Justin thought it was
really neat and I think it's something
we should all like be like leaning into
and working on and looking into. Um
super thankful for your all's time and
attention and I hope that you enjoyed
the episode and we'll see you in another
week.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh or if
you want to support the show, head over
to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild
if you're a full-time hunter. It's a
great time, trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.